SAMMY SAMKOUGH

862-239-0100 | sammysamkough@gmail.com | Wayne, NJ 07470; New York City, NY 10001 https://sammy.pizza | https://github.com/ssamkough | https://linkedin.com/in/ssamkough

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER; HARRIS FOR PRESIDENT

SUMMARY:

Web Developer with 5+ years of industry experience developing websites that are responsive and that work across multiple devices and browsers. With strong team and project management skills, using HTML, CSS, JS, and Wordpress.

Areas of Expertise: WEB DEVELOPMENT // HTML, CSS, JS // WORDPRESS

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES:

- Languages HTML; CSS; JavaScript; TypeScript; Python; C#; Java; SQL; PHP
- Frameworks React.js; Next.js; Remix; Astro.js; SASS; Svelte; Django; Node.js; Express.js; React Native
- Applications Git; Figma; PostgreSQL; GraphQL; Storybook; AWS; Google Cloud; Vercel; Netlify; Chromatic

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Bonny Systems, New York City, NY; Wayne, NJ

Oct 2023 - Present

Founding Engineer

- Achieving over 80% reduction in website load times by improving core web vitals which includes minimizing JavaScript usage, image optimization, and adherence to web standards.
- Partnering with design agencies to build and deploy modern websites / landing pages with CI/CD pipelines using content management systems (CMS) like WordPress or advanced front-end frameworks such as Next.js and Astro.js.

Canal, San Francisco, CA; New York City, NY

May 2021 - Jul 2023

Software Engineer

- Developed the onboarding process to adapt to evolving user needs, making product decisions on the fly, utilizing React, Next.js, TypeScript, XState, Django and GraphQL which lead to an overall 40% increase in user satisfaction.
- Collaborated with a fast-moving design / product team of five to create in-house design system that replaced the Shopify Polaris design system which led to an increase of development speed by over 60%.
- Enhanced web application usability across all departments by 60% through leading targeted accessibility training and guidelines for the development team.
- Led the standardization of UI / UX component testing within the in-house design system, significantly reducing component-specific bugs by over 70% and increasing quality assurance using Chromatic and Storybook.

Popstar, Remote USA

Nov 2020 - Apr 2021

Software Engineer

- Launched a feature-rich iOS application using Swift and Firebase / NoSQL, which offered an elegant vertical video experience, including social interactions such as sharing and commenting on videos.
- Integrated backend Firebase push notifications and cloud messaging enhancing user engagement by 80%.

Decusoft, Hybrid (Ramsey, NJ; Remote USA)

May 2019 - Oct 2020

Full Stack Software Developer

- Implemented table features like filtering and sorting algorithms using JavaScript, C# / ASP.NET and SQL.
- Optimized complex SQL queries which increased the load time performance of the main MySQL table by 50%.

EDUCATION: